Sean McCarthy

(336) 817-3773 | Cary, NC | <u>sean.mccarthy703@gmail.com</u> mctastic msmccarthydev Portfolio|https://sean-m-portfolio.vercel.app/

Freelance Full Stack Web Developer

Dedicated MERN stack developer with a demonstrated history of working in the service and technology industries. Experienced in CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Material UI, Materialize, jQuery, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Next.js, MongoDB, SQL, and Git with a fundamental understanding of object-oriented programming and agile methodology.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE PROJECTS

Room & Bord - https://www.roomandbord-arch.com

Jan 2024

Full stack website with a basic custom-built CMS for a San Diego based architect. Built with Next.js and all custom CSS. Treely (WORK IN PROGRESS) - https://treely-beige.vercel.app

April 2024

Built with Next.js - displays the works of a holiday decoration company. Uses Aceternity UI components and Tailwind.

Instructional Support Specialist- Full Stack Bootcamp | 2U

March 2022 -

Assist with guidance and instructing people on the MERN stack for web development. This includes guidance when stuck and instructing on how basic concepts work as well as helping to bug test projects to get people back on track with their applications.

- Teaching MERN stack to people new to coding
- Evaluating/grading projects submitted
- Breaking down complex coding concepts to people not familiar with them

Supervisor - Conduent | Raleigh, NC

Jan. 2019 - Jul. 2021

Managed team of 15 to 30 help desk agents representing a significant multinational technology company specializing in consumer electronics. Worked with operations manager and quality assurance teams to help agents improve and develop customer service and troubleshooting skills.

- Oversaw team with the highest customer satisfaction score over the course of one month.
- Maintained above 90% customer satisfaction score and QA score on calls.
- Routinely calibrated at 100% on strict internal evaluations.

Quality Assurance Analyst- Conduent | Raleigh, NC

Nov. 2017 - Jan. 2019

Performed routine quality evaluations on help desk agents, both remotely and in-person. Mentored new hires and educated them on troubleshooting technical issues, handling customers in a professional manner, and following proper business procedures.

- Supported a team of 60 outliers and assisted in raising issue resolution from below 70% to above 90%.
- Oversaw team with the highest customer satisfaction score over the course of one month.
- Assisted multiple agents with developing skills that reduced case handle time from 30 minutes to 15 minutes.

Tier II Help Desk Agent Conduent | Raleigh, NC

May 2016 - Nov. 2017

Provided Tier I and Tier II technical assistance for a Fortune 500 client to upwards of 50+ end users daily. Communicated with the Engineering team to resolve complex technical issues. Maintained contact with end users to ensure issue resolution and customer satisfaction.

- Resolved 95% of issues during the first contact with the customer.
- Consistently ranked within the top 10 help desk agents out of 500 total agents.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Boot Camp | UNC Chapel Hill - Professional Certificate

Jul. 2021 – Jan. 2022

Acquired skills in MERN stack development, databases, API interaction, and basic computer science concepts.

PROJECTS

PTC Binder https://ptcbinder.vercel.app

Full stack application that allows registered users to track which Pokémon cards they have in their personal collection using MongoDB for the database and Next.js

Chat App | https://chill-chat.onrender.com

Fun little chat application that utilizes the Remix.js React framework and web sockets (socket-io). Allows users to chat with one another in the designated chat room that they choose.